josef heidegger

Wiener Straße 60-62/2/12, 3400 Klosterneuburg, Austria

contact

- m josef.heidegger@outlook.at
- p +43 699 1967 58 68
- w https://sendit.space

Automate all the things!

Accomplished team lead with more than 9 years of industry experience in product and project/agency environments.

Adept in people mentoring and management, hiring and technical interviews, agile methodologies, product management, delivery processes and development practices with a strong technical background.

experience

2016-08 – 2020-04 (3.7Y) Lead Developer Tablet Solutions GmbH

Lead of the development team (5ppl) of a SaaS startup in the field of industrial construction.

In my role as technical lead I took a big part in lifting the product from an early MVP into a robust, highly customizable SaaS platform that it is now.

Responsible for the engineering department, I recruited most of the development and QA team, set up technical standards and guidelines, introduced BDD into our development process, added test automation and production monitoring practices and steadily improved our release process into the Continuous Delivery approach.

Also implemented and shaped the agile mindset of the company as Scrum Master.

2011-01 - 2016-07 (5.5Y) Software Developer EMAKINA CEE (formerly diamond:dogs gmbh)

IC for various projects for Austrian and international customers.

Had the opportunity to work with great minds and get a fundamental understanding of state-of-the-art software development practices. Was also getting some very good management and life lessons from some great team leads.

Most prominent project from a complexity perspective was a .NET/Angular SPA for (§57a) vehicle safety inspection that was rolled out nationwide.

education

2006 – 2009 Software Engineering

University of Applied Sciences Upper Austria, Campus Hagenberg

1997 – 2005 BG/BRG Gmunden

languages

German Native (C2)
English Proficient (C1)
French Basic (A1)

certifications

2018 Certified Scrum Master (Scrum Alliance)

personal

Always up to new things and interested in learning new methodologies and technology (ofc). Other hobbies are sports (active and passive), nature, photography and history.

skills

People and Leadership

- coaching, mentoring & sponsorship
- hiring & technical interviews
- strong sense of ownership
- very approachable and helpful
- empathic
- strong team spirit
- sense of humor
- open minded
- sharp mind and good problemsolving skills

Product and Project

- Agile/SCRUM
- SaaS Product Development
- Domain Driven Design
- Behaviour Driven Development
- Test Driven Development
- Requirements Engineering
- Release Planning
- Technical Concepts
- Code reviews
- Story Pattern
- Test Automation
- CI/CD
- GitFlow
- Trunk Based Development
- Semantic Versioning
- API Design
- Jira/Confluence
- GitHub
- Azure DevOps

Development and DevOps

- Git
- C#
- TypeScript
- JavaScript
- .NET
- Angular
- Xamarin
- SQL (MSSQL/SQLite)
- EF Core
- ASP.NET Core
- HTML/CSS
- RESTful APIs
- Swagger
- Cloud Computing
- Azure
- AWS
- Micro Services
- Serverless
- Docker
- UWP
- Android
- Azure DevOps
- TeamCity
- ELK
- elastic
- redis
 - PowerShell
- Tomcat
- IIS